抓捕与释放
欢迎关注微博@ UUU字幕组 获取最新熟肉信息!
出品
presisco
翻译
零玖/ presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
"catch and release"还是一种钓鱼方式--就是钓完以后再放回去
看到右侧的GBA了吗?
晚安 欢乐熊
Good night, happy bear.
晚安 忧伤兔 晚安 玩乐猫
Good night, sad bunny. Good night, playful kitty.
晚安 床头不详的三角形
Good night, ominous triangle at the foot of my bed.
注意橄榄石右侧的"动物之森"游戏光盘
管他呢
Whatever.
让我走吧!
Ah! Let me go!
够了
Enough of this.
你想要我什么?
What do you want from me?
我想离开这个讨厌的宝石抛弃了的星球
I want to get off this lousy gem-forsaken planet.
你一定得修好这个!
You have to fix this.
等等 什么?
Wait, what?
你是我最后的机会了 我没有烧瓶机器人了
You're my last chance. I've got no flask robonoids.
我也没有脚了
I've got no foot.
我到现在还没收到黄钻石的回应
I've got no response from yellow diamond.
我知道你修复了青金石的宝石
I know you fixed Lazuli's gem.
不论你做什么 你一定得对通往母世界的传送台照做
Whatever you did, you've got to do it to the homeworld warp.
否则!
Or else!
呃 好的 只要-只要给我一点时间
Uh, okay. Just--just give me a second.
我受惊吓时嘴会变得很干
My mouth gets really dry when I'm scared.
来吧
Here goes.
那是什么? 一点效果都没有啊!
What was that? It didn't do anything!
这并不总是起作用
It doesn't always work.
不
No.
不不不不不! 这一定得起作用啊!
No, no, no, no, no! It has to work!
我实在抱歉
I'm really sorry.
就这样吧 我的最后的尝试
This was it. This was my last shot.
我会死在这里的
I'm gonna die here.
哦
Ohhh.
嘿 嘿 别啊 地球也没那么遭
Hey, hey, come on. Earth isn't that bad.
地球怎么样无所谓
It doesn't matter what earth is like.
反正不久之后就没样子了
It's not going to be like anything soon.
你是指?
What do you mean?
他在那!
There he is.
各位!
Guys!
发生了什么? 噢 你没事就好!
What happened? Oh, you're okay!
橄榄石!
Peridot!
为什么你们就不能离我远点!
Why can't you just leave me alone?
宝石人们 上!
Gems, move!
哈!
Ha!
这次可别想了
Not this time.
等等 等等 你-你们需要我
Wait, wait. You--you need me.
我是唯一一个知道-
I'm the only one who knows about the--
什么鬼东西?
What on earth?
呃 真恶心 她的碎片掉了一地
Ugh, sick. There's bits of her all over.
不 她在这里
Nope. She's right here.
现在她在庙里了
And now she's in the temple.
那么 这些并不算她身体的一部分?
So, these weren't actually part of her body?
呃 哎呀
Uh, whoops.
石榴 她刚才试图告诉我们什么
Garnet, she was trying to tell us something.
那只是被抓住的宝石人的绝望挣扎
Those are just the desperate lies of a gem who's been caught.
你不用再担心她了
You don't need to worry about her anymore.
来吧 史蒂文
Come on, Steven.
哦 我很高兴这总算结束了
Oh, I'm so glad this is finally over.
我回来绑架你了!
I'm back to kidnap you!
怎么?
What?
过了这么久现在已经能用来开玩笑了 对吧?
It's been long enough that we can joke about it, right?
才过了大概一小时吧
It's only been like an hour.
那么 呃 你拿着她的脚干嘛?
So, ew, what are you doing with her foot?
觉得能带来好运吗?
Think it's lucky?
在某些文化中兔子的脚能带来好运
橄榄石可无福消受
Not for Peridot.
那么 很高兴你回来
Well, glad to have you back.
呃...紫晶?
Um...Amethyst?
怎么?
Yeah?
呃...你觉得...
Uh...Do you think...
没什么 别在意
No, it's okay. Never mind.
好吧 怪胎
Okay, weirdo.
如果你需要任何东西 我一直在我的房间-吃垃圾
If you need anything, I'll be in my room eating garbage.
好的
Okay.
为什么你那么害怕? 你本要说什么?
Why were you so scared? What were you going to say?
现在你被困在神庙深处的泡泡里 而我们也永远不会知道了
Now you're deep in the temple in a bubble and we'll never know.
如果我有机会和你再多交流一秒...
If I could just talk to you for one more second...
房间 我要和橄榄石谈话
Room, I need to talk to Peridot.
我是唯一一个知道-
I'm the only one who knows about the--
什么啊?
the what?!
呃 不不不
Ugh. No, no, no.
房间 我要去地下室
Room, I need to go to the basement.
真正的地下室
The real basement.
我知道有通道下去
I know there's a way down from here.
谢谢!
Thank you!
喔! 爽! 喔～呼!
Whoo! Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
三层550度豪华版 不要奶酪!
Triple 550 deluxe with no cheese!
没错 完美着陆
Yep. Perfect landing.
嗯...
Hmm...
就是那个
There we go.
抓到你了!
Gotcha!
喔!
Whoa!
...融合簇的人 你们这群恼人 半吊子
...the cluster, you insufferable, half-formed,
叛徒超级大草包!
traitor megaclods!
哦 我的天!
Oh, my gosh!
你真是太可爱了!
You're so cute!
我的肢体增强器! 我的肢体增强器在哪?!
My limb enhancers! Where are my limb enhancers?!
嗷! 你就像一片小小的生气的派
Aww! You're like an angry little slice of pie.
蹩说话
Stop talking.
"stop talking"和傲娇的姿势与"日常工作"的Rigby 啧啧
我要求对此地的详细介绍与我在-
I demand to know what this place is and where I--
哦 我的星星啊 你们打算收割我?
oh, my stars. You're going to harvest me?
不 我-我是指...
No. I-I mean...
嗷 那很疼的!
Ow! That hurt!
真的?
It did?
对 非常疼
Yeah. A lot.
嗷!
Ow!
好啊! 感受我脱缰的狂怒吧!
Yes! Feel my unbridled rage!
嘿! 嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey, hey.
你衬衫上的是什么?
What's that on your shirt?
什么是衬衫?
What's a shirt?
嗷!
Ow!
够了!
That's it!
你为什么非得这样?
Why are you acting like this?
你们把我搞成了没有肢体的草包!
You smashed me into a limbless clod!
你们把我困在你们的泡泡地牢!
You trapped me in your bubble dungeon!
而且 你居然成我 可爱!
And you called me cute!
我又没有捅破你
I didn't poof you.
我解救了你
I freed you.
为什么你会如此失算?
Why would you make such a miscalculation?
在传送台的时候 你本打算说什么?
Back at the warp pad, what were you trying to say?
为什么我们需要你? 你都知道什么?
Why do we need you? What do you know?
我知道什么?
What do I know?
所有有关融合簇的信息 你个笨石头
Everything there is to know about the cluster, you pebble.
融合簇? 等等 笨石头?
Cluster? Wait, pebble?
我的任务
My mission,
我被困在这个破烂石头上的首要原因
the reason why I'm on this sad rock in the first place.
我本要检查融合簇的进展
I was to check progress on the cluster.
只是在孵化前来看一眼
Just in and out before it hatches.
我本不应被困在这里
I wasn't supposed to get stuck here.
但现在它将孵化 而谁都没法阻止它
But now it's going to emerge and nothing can stop it,
而我们都将被粉碎!
and we'll all be shattered!
好吧 好吧 等等 别急
Okay, okay. Wait, slow down.
现在 从头再来
Now, from the top.
正在孕育 即将孵化的融合簇
Emerging, hatching clusters.
你想知道吗?
You want to know?
没错
Yes.
你真的想知道?
You really want to know?
对
Yes.
这是你的衬衫?
What's your shirt?
这是我的香蕉睡衣
These are my banana pajamas.
此处"香蕉睡衣"致敬儿童剧"睡衣香蕉人"
嗷! 等等 别跑啊!
Ow! Wait, don't run away!
停下! 她们会看见你的!
Stop! They're gonna see you!
自由是属于我的!
Freedom is mine!
等等!
Wait!
看那里! 又一个叛变的星球!
Look, over there! Another planet to betray!
撤退!
Retreat!
哦不 你可别想!
Oh, no you don't!
嘿
Hey.
呃啊啊啊!
Aaah!
抓住她!
Get her!
你们也许赢得了战争
You may have won the war,
但战斗远未结束 水晶草包!
but the battle isn't over, crystal clods!
我们该告诉她那是厕所吗?
Should we tell her that's the bathroom?
呃...
Eh.
嗯...
Hmm.
看来我发现了某种古老的-
Seems I discovered some sort of archaic--
冥想区域
think chamber.
空间很大 带有地球柠檬的清香
Roomy, with a fresh hint of earth citrus.
我逃跑的完美路口
A perfect crossroads for my escape.
被锁上了
It's locked.
橄榄石 快开门
Peridot, open the door.
呃 如果你试图将自己从马桶冲下去的话
Uh, if you're trying to flush yourself down the toilet,
这没用的
it won't work.
相信我 我试过
Trust me. I've tried.
她是怎么逃出来的? 我们用泡泡包住她了
How did she get out? We bubbled her.
也许我们需要更大的泡泡
Maybe we needed a bigger bubble.
我的泡泡没问题
My bubbles are fine.
我做的
I did it.
史蒂文 为什么你要这么做?
Steven, why would you do such a thing?
因为她知道些东西
Because she knows something,
某些让她害怕的东西
something that's made her scared.
切 闺蜜知道我们会把她揍成绿色烙饼的
Duh. Homegirl knows we're gonna beat her into a green pancake.
不 不是因为我们
No, not 'cause of us.
因为某种叫"融合簇"的东西
'Cause of something called "the cluster."
融合簇?
Cluster?
这可没听过
That's new.
她还告诉你什么了?
What else did she tell you?
我就知道这些
That's all I got.
没错 你们这群土鳖
That's right, you dirt bombs.
你们甚至都不知要面对什么
You don't even know what's coming.
噢!
Oh!
我厌倦与这种宝石人交涉了
I'm tired of playing these games.
如果我们不能打她 那么好
If we can't fight her, then fine.
我们可以谈判
We'll talk.
橄榄石!
Peridot!
喔!
Whoa!
好吧 我们不要再打了
All right, no more fighting.
让我们进行礼貌的对话吧
Let's just have a civil conversation.
好像我会和你谈判一样 肮脏的战争机器!
As if I'd negotiate with you, filthy war machine!
好吧 让我们爆她菊
Okay, let's kick her butt.
等等!
Wait!
对 再次摧毁我吧
Yeah, destroy me again.
而且欢迎试着和困在泡泡中的我谈话
And have fun trying to talk to me when I'm in a bubble.
我真的很不想说 但不幸的是
I really hate to say it, but unfortunately,
如果她有信息 她现在这样反而更好
if she has information, she's more valuable to us like this.
这就不好办了
This is going to be tricky.
烫烫烫烫!
Hot, hot, hot, hot!
你得将水龙头拧向另一边才会变冷
You have to turn the knob the other way for cold.
等等 那么我们就得让她住在我的卫生间里?
Wait, so we're just gonna let her live in my bathroom?
其实 没错 我们还有什么选择?
Well, yes. What other option do we have?
用绳子将她绑在外面?
Keep her outside on a leash?
嗯...
Hmm.
但我需要用厕所啊
But I need to use the bathroom.
现在?
Right now?
对 算是
Yeah, kinda.
去海里吧 兄弟
Just go in the ocean, bro.
像鱼一样
Like a fish.
你们几个让我在外面尿是几个意思?
What's with you guys and making me pee outside?
呃 我反正喜欢这样
Well, I have fun doing it.
哦 但即使我们将她从厕所里弄出来了
Oh, but even if we do get her to come out of the bathroom...
她也不会和我们说的
She's never gonna talk to us.
看来我们现在也没什么好做的
Looks like there's not much else we can do right now.
我们至少将她拘禁起来了
We have her in our custody at least,
橄榄石 我能进来吗? 我需要为一天做好准备
Peridot, can I come in? I need to get ready for the day.
即使情况看起来并不乐观
even if the circumstances are less than optimal.
不行
No.
你觉得融合簇的信息有多重要?
How important do you think this Cluster is?
我有东西给你
I have something for you.
如果这和那些
If it has anything to do with the experiment
她在幼儿园进行的实验有关 那么非常重要
she was conducting in the kindergarten, then very.
多么好的一个纪念品 用来纪念你冒犯我的另一次
What a great souvenir of that other time you assaulted me.
哦 对 对不起 我将它收回吧
Oh, right. Sorry. I can take it back.
不 已经太迟了
No, it's too late.
你不会刚好有其他的吧?
You wouldn't happen to have the rest?
呃 对不起 我们弄丢了
Uh, sorry. We lost them.
其实 我们差不多将它们扔了
Well, we kind of threw them away.
你能递给我那个吗?
Can you pass me that?
这是武器吗?
Is this a weapon?
对蛀牙来说是的
Only for cavities.
嗯 谢谢
Hmm. Thanks.
这是武器吗?
Is that a weapon?
不 那是我从没用过的一个梳子
No. That's a comb I never use.
这是武器吗?
Is that a weapon?
嗯? 哦 其实 我猜如果你把它打湿 然后卷起来 就应该是了
Hmm? Oh, well, I guess if you get it wet and roll it up.
啊!
Aah!
听着 我知道你很害怕
Look, I know you're scared,
但我不会伤害你的
but I'm not going to hurt you.
并且无论发生了什么
And whatever's going on,
不论融合簇是什么 我都想帮忙
whatever the cluster is, I want to help.
我不信你能帮到我
I doubt you can help me.
但我...很感谢你的邀请
But I...Appreciate the offer.
现在 你介意挪一下吗? 我得用那个了
Now, do you mind moving? I have to use that.
用来干吗?
For what?
我认为我非常卑微
♪ I always thought I might be bad ♪
现在我已确定
♪ now I'm sure that it's true
因 你如此完美
♪ 'cause I think you're so good ♪
而我却丝毫不如
♪ and I'm nothing like you